# **Jason Huang**

jason.huang@ucalgary.ca github.com/jasonhuang2 jasonhuang2.github.io

# **PROFILE**

Outgoing and passionate computer science student with two years of object-oriented programming and information security experience. Demonstrated leadership with experience in software development with solid programming skills. Eager to learn new skills and take on new challenges to succeed in multi-disciplinary environments.

# SKILLS/STRENGTHS

#### **Technologies/Environment**:

 Unix OS, MS Windows, Apple macOS, Google Android, Xcode, RESTful API, MS Azure

#### Interpersonal:

- Ability to adapt quickly to challenges and changing environments
- Highly collaborative with team members in multi-disciplinary environments
- Able to balance priorities and meet deadlines under pressure
- Self-motivated, innovative and willing to assume responsibilities

### **Programming languages:**

 Java, C, C++, C#, Swift, Python, SQL, Perl, Assembly, Haskell, LaTeX, Pro\*C, HTML, CSS, JSON

#### Theoretical:

- Performed extensive customer collaboration to establish functional requirements
- Designed a software engineer project in a data base management course (Will's Library)
- Generated concrete, robust test cases to validate requirements
- Familiarity with cryptography and cyber-security

# **PROJECTS**

#### Chevron's GENV Log Merge Script

- Merge multiple .las logs into one Microsoft Excel with the computed percentile, missing mnemonics, and missing units for petrophysicists
- Implementation of technology saved over 1,000 hours of labour by reducing repetitive, manual work

#### Chevron's WebDEF API

- Interface for communication between Chevron's on-premise's data base and Microsoft's Azure Cloud
- Utilization of Microsoft's Cloud Technology to enhance Chevron's flexibility, scalability, and reduce IT spending

#### FileEncrypter V2.0 Program

- User GUI friendly interface that can securely decrypt and encrypt user's choice of file
- Utilizes cryptographic algorithm AES-256 and data integrity through HMAC SHA-1

#### Will's Library Mobile App

- Tracked, updated, and displayed library's inventory in real time
- Administrator and client's ability to check-out library item(s) and pay outstanding fees

#### **QuoteSeeker iOS App**

- Searches for quotes based on user inputted author and/or genre
- Utilizes RESTful API and JSON file format

# **EDUCATION**

### **Bachelor of Science, Computer Science**

**September 2015 – June 2021** 

University of Calgary, Calgary, AB

- Area of Specialization: Information Security
- Cumulative GPA: 3.35/4.0
- Related Focus: Cryptography, Data Base Management, Computer Networks, Android App Development, API, EF Framework

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **Chevron Canada Resources**

January 2019 – December 2019

Application Support Intern (Full Time)

- Assisted Chevron by accelerating the digital transformation to Cloud technology to ensure optimization of operations, increase revenue and enabling advanced technologies
- Participated in script enhancement to automate repetitive tasks and reconstruct data record
- Designed and constructed an API interface to communicate between Microsoft's Azure Cloud and Chevron's on-premise's core infrastructure

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Property Management Assistant**

April 2011 – Present

Self Employed (Part Time)

- Demonstrate strong verbal communication with all parties to ensure mutual satisfaction
- Manages several residents; includes searching for tenants, conduct walkthroughs, and scheduling/organizing lease signing
- Assure tenants are provided with access to vital services in an immediate and attentive manner

### PERSONAL INTERESTS

- App Development: mobile app development for Android and iOS
- Traveling: explore new countries and experience its culture
- **Hiking**: vigorous hikes in the countryside
- Long Distance Running: half-marathon / marathon enthusiastic
- Weightlifting: strength training